Guide to the New York University Archives Photograph Collection PHOTO.00001
New York University Archives
- Washington Square Area, 166005
  - West 4th Street, 166032 (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - 4th Street Between Greene and Mercer, 1964; wsa_5_4_03; 166057; Luigi Pellettieri; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 3)
    - 4th Street, 1964; wsa_5_4_04; 166056; Luigi Pellettieri; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 4)
    - Fraternity Street at Mercer Street, undated; wsa_5_4_05; 166055; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 5)
    - Arm Holding Candle, Psi Upsilon Fraternity, undated; wsa_5_4_06; 166054; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 6)
    - 40 West 4th Street, 1976; wsa_5_4_07; 166053; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Fraternity Building, untitled; wsa_5_4_08; 166052; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 8)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_09; 166051; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 9)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_10; 166050; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 10)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_11; 166049; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 11)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_12; 166048; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 12)
    - Park, West 3rd, undated; wsa_5_4_13; 166047; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 13)
    - Park, West 3rd, undated; wsa_5_4_14; 166046; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 14)
    - Park, West 3rd, undated; wsa_5_4_15; 166045; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 15)
    - Fraternity House, 1979; wsa_5_4_16; 166044; Chin, Danny; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 16)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_17; 166043; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 17)
    - Chess Tables, West 4th at Sixth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_4_18; 166042; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 18)
    - West 4th Street and Mercer, 1970; wsa_5_4_19; 166041; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 19)
    - West Fourth Street Resurfacing, undated; wsa_5_4_20; 166040; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 20)
    - West 4th and Mercer, 1970; wsa_5_4_21; 166039; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 21)
    - 37 Washington Square West, 1962; wsa_5_4_22; 166038; Luigi Pellettieri; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 22)
    - Corner of West 4th and Washington Square West, 1962; wsa_5_4_23; 166037; Luigi Pellettieri; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 23)
    - George B. Burnett and Son, West 4th and Greene, undated; wsa_5_4_24; 166036; Sihler, Henry J.; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 24)
    - West Broadway and West 4t Street and Washington Square South, undated; wsa_5_4_25; 166035; Sihler, Henry J.; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 25)
    - Corner of West 4th and Greene, 1935; wsa_5_4_26; 166034; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 26)
    - Unidentified Street, 1970; wsa_5_4_27; 166033; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 1, Item 27)
  - West 8th Street, 166025 (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - South Side of West 8th Street Looking from Fifth Avenue, undated; wsa_5_5_01; 166031; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 1)
    - South Side of East 8th Street Looking West from University Place, 1949; wsa_5_5_02; 166030; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 2)
    - 8th Street, undated; wsa_5_5_03; 166029; Winzelberg; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 3)
    - South Side of West 8th Street Looking East from Sixth Avenue, 1945; wsa_5_5_04; 166028; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 4)
    - South Side of West 8th Street Looking West from MacDougal Street, 1945; wsa_5_5_05; 166027; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 5)
    - South Side of West 8th Street Looking East from MacDougal Street, 1945; wsa_5_5_06; 166026 (Box 182, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - West 11th Street "Bomb Factory" (Weathermen Townhouse), 166019 (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - 11th Street Townhouse (Bomb Factory), undated; wsa_5_6_01; 166024; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - House Blown Up By Weathermen, 1980; wsa_5_6_02; 166023; Chin, Danny; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 3, Item 2)
    - House Blown Up By Weathermen, 1980; wsa_5_6_03; 166022; Chin, Danny; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 3, Item 3)
    - 11th Street Townhouse (Bomb Factory), undated; wsa_5_6_04; 166021; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 3, Item 4)
    - 11th Street Townhouse (Bomb Factory), undated; wsa_5_6_05; 166020; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 8 inches (Box 182, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - West 11th Street #34 - Chancellor's Residence, 1966; 166012 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - 34 West 11th Street, Backyard, 1967; wsa_5_7_01; 166018; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 1)
    - Chancellor's House, 34 West 11th Street, 1967; wsa_5_7_02; 166017; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 2)
    - Chancellor's House, 34 West 11th Street, 1967; wsa_5_7_03; 166016; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 3)
    - Chancellor's House, 34 West 11th Street, 1966; wsa_5_7_04; 166015; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 4)
    - Chancellor's House, 34 West 11th Street, 1966; wsa_5_7_05; 166014; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 5)
    - Chancellor's House, 34 West 11th Street, 1966; wsa_5_7_06; 166013; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - the Violet (Coffee Shop), 166010 (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - Students in Violet Cafe, circa 1990; wsa_5_8_01; 166011; Pelaez, Jose; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Wooster Street, 166006 (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - West Side of Wooster Street Looking North from West Third Street, undated; wsa_5_9_01; 166009; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 6, Item 1)
    - West Side of Wooster Street Looking South from West 4th Street, undated; wsa_5_9_02; 166008; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 6, Item 2)
    - East Side of West Broadway Looking North from West 3rd Street, undated; wsa_5_9_03; 166007; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 182, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Washington Square Area -- Negative, 248350 (Item 14)
- University Building, 1832-1894; 165869 (Box 246, Folder 1)
  Arrangement note
  The photos are arranged by type of view (exterior and interior). Exterior views are arranged chronologically. Interior views are arranged by subject (type of room).
  Biographical/Historical note
  The University Building was constructed on the northeast corner of the park between Washington Place and Waverly Place in 1833-34. Architects Ithiel Town, Alexander Jackson Davis, and James Dakin as well as NYU engineering professor David B. Douglass designed the university's first building in the Gothic Revival-style. This type of architectural style was meant to evoke the medieval buildings of Oxford and Cambridge and link the more modern and practical American curriculum the university was founded on to the long, rich tradition of English education.
  Initially, the building was too large for the student body to fill so residential rooms, studios, and laboratories were rented out to a variety of artists and inventors including Winslow Homer and Samuel F.B. Morse. In the late 19th century as the university expanded, the undergraduate college moved to the more spacious University Heights campus in the Bronx initially leading to the decline of the Washington Square campus and in 1894 the University Building was demolished.
  Sources:
  "The University Building." The University Quarterly 17 (May 1894): 116-123. "University Building." New York University Education Quarterly (Spring 1981): 20.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains photographs and prints of the interior and exterior of the University Building as well as the immediate surrounding area.
  - University Building - Exterior, 1832, Proposed Design by A.J. Davis, 166001; Wilson, A.J. (Box 246, Folder 1)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1832; CB_UB_1_1_01; 166004; Wilson, A.J.; black-and-white print (photograph), 2 x 2 inches. Image is from page in unidentified publication: New York, Saturday, September 13, 1834, Vol. XII. (Box 246, Folder 1, Item 1)
      New York University -- Buildings.; Washington Square (New York, N.Y.)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1832; CB_UB_1_1_02; 166003; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches (Box 246, Folder 1, Item 2)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Not for Reproduction: Property of the New York Historical Society
      Washington Square (New York, N.Y.); New York University -- Buildings.
    - University Building, Exterior, 1832; CB_UB_1_1_03; 166002; illustration, 2 x 2 inches. Image is from page in publication: Catalog, 1856. (Box 246, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - University Building - Exterior, c. 1833, Watercolor & Engraving, A.J. Davis, 165997 (Box 246, Folder 2)
    - University Building, Exterior, circa 1833; CB_UB_1_2_01; 166000; black-and-white print (photograph), 2 x 2 inches. Image is of a montage of illustrations. (Box 246, Folder 2, Item 1)
      Not for Reproduction: Property of Metropolitan Museum of Art
    - University Building, Exterior, circa 1833; CB_UB_1_2_02; 165999; Davis, Alexander Jackson; color print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches. Image is of a watercolor painting. (Box 246, Folder 2, Item 2)
      Not for Reproduction: Property of the Metropolitan Museum of Art
    - University Building, Exterior, circa 1833; CB_UB_1_2_03; 165998; illustration, 3 x 4.5 inches. Image is from page in unidentified publication (page with title: New York University, Alumnus, p. 13). (Box 246, Folder 2, Item 3)
      Not for Reproduction: Propert of New York Historical Society
  - University Building - Exterior, 1834, N.Y. Mirror View, 165994 (Box 246, Folder 3)
    - University Building, Exterior elevation and building plan, 1834; CB_UB_1_3_01; 165996; Town Davis Dakin Douglas. Architects; black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches. Image is of exterior elevation and building plan. (Box 246, Folder 3, Item 1)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1834; CB_UB_1_3_02; 165995; black-and-white negative, 3 x 4 inches. Image is of cover page of publication: New-York Mirror, 1834 September, 13. (Box 246, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1836, Allegorical Landscape by Samuel F.B. Morse, 165992 (Box 246, Folder 4)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1836; CB_UB_1_4_01; 165993; Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872 (Box 246, Folder 4, Item 1)
      black-and-white print (photograph), 8 x 10 inches. Image is of a painting.
      New York University -- Buildings.
  - University Building - Exterior, 1836, Hinshelwood Engraving, 165989 (Box 246, Folder 5)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1836; CB_UB_1_5_01; 165991; Hinshelwood, Robert (Box 246, Folder 5, Item 1)
      engraving (print), 2.75 x 3.75 inches
    - University Building, Exterior, 1836; CB_UB_1_5_02; 165990; black-and-white print (photocopy) 8 x 10 inches of engraving (print) (Box 246, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1836, Elevation and Plan by Town, Davis, Dakin & Douglas. Diary Excerpts, A.J. Davis, 165986 (Box 246, Folder 6)
    - University Building, Exterior elevation and building plan, 1836; CB_UB_1_6_01; 165988; Town Davis Dakin Douglas. Architects; negative print, 8 x 10 inches. Image is of exterior elevation and building plan. (Box 246, Folder 6, Item 1)
    - University Building, Exterior elevation and building plan, 1836; CB_UB_1_6_02; 165987; Town Davis Dakin Douglas. Architects; black-and-white print (photocopy) 8 x 10 inches of engraving (print) (Box 246, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1837-1930s, Views from University Publications & Printed Materials, circa 1837-1939; 165978 (Box 246, Folder 7)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1837 July 20; CB_UB_1_7_01; 165985; black-and-white negative, 3 x 4 inches. Image is of illustration, reprinted in rural repository (1846) and Mason's Discourse (1847) (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 1)
    - University Building, Exterior, circa 1936; CB_UB_1_7_02; 165984; Engraving, 2.5 x 1.75 inches. Image is from flyer (printed matter): "New York Univeristy presented by The Society for the Libraries." (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 2)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1935; CB_UB_1_7_03; 165983; illustration, 3.5 x 4.5 inches. Image is from an invitation pamphlet: "New York Univeristy Council Dinner, Tuesday, June Eleventh, Nineteen Thirty-five, The Waldorf-Astoria, New York." (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 3)
    - University Building, Exterior, probably 1848; CB_UB_1_7_04; 165982; illustration, 3.75 x 5.75 inches. Image is from page in unidentified publication (page with title: "Pictorial Library of Useful Information," p. 409). (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 4)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1835; CB_UB_1_7_05; 165981; black-and-white print, 3 x 4 inches of engraving. Image is of a montage of photographs. (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 5)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1861-1863; CB_UB_1_7_06; 165980; Engraving, 4.25 x 5 inches. Image is from catalog (1861-1862) frontispiece. (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 6)
    - University Building, Partial Exterior, 1934; CB_UB_1_7_07; 165979; Engraving, 3.125 x 3.625 inches. Image is from publication: The Album, 1934, p. 25. (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 7)
    - University Building, Exterior, circa 1896; CB_UB_1_7_08; 177019; Engraving (enlarged), 5 x 4 inches. Image is from publication: Lamb, Martha J., and Mrs. Burton Harrison. History of the City of New York: Its Origin Rise, and Progress. Volume 3. New York: A.S. Barnes, 1896, p. 719. Artist and engraver unspecified, although artists and engravers whose works appear in the volume are listed on page xi. (Box 246, Folder 7, Item 8)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1844, Valentine's Manual View, 165976 (Box 246, Folder 8)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1844; CB_UB_1_8_01; 165977; Illustration, 4.5 x 3.125 inches. Image is from publication: Valentine's Manual, 1844. (Box 246, Folder 8, Item 1)
      Not for Reproduction: Property of Metropolitan Museum of Art.
  - University Building - Exterior, 1846, Rural Repository (Same as commencement ticket, 1837) View, 165974 (Box 246, Folder 9)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1846; CB_UB_1_9_01; 165975; Engraving, 4.5 x 2.5 inches. Image is from publication: Rural Repository, June 20, 1846, Vol. 22, Number 21, p. 1. (Box 246, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1847, View From Discourse... by C. Mason (Same as Rural Repository, 1846), 165972 (Box 246, Folder 10)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1847; CB_UB_1_10_01; 165973; Engraving, 4 x 3.125 inches. Image is from publication: C. Mason, The Growth--University City of New York, a Discourse... (Box 246, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1848, Pictorial Library of Useful Information, Vol 2, Number 10, 165970 (Box 246, Folder 11)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1848; CB_UB_1_11_01; 165971; Engraving, 2 x 4. Image is from publication: Pictorial Library of Useful Information, 1848?. (Box 246, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1850, Hoff View, 165968; Illustration, 7.5 x 6 inches. Hoff View. (Box 246, Folder 12)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1850; CB_UB_1_12_01; 165969; Black-and-white (print), 4 x 6 inches, engraving. Hoff view. (Box 246, Folder 12, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, c. 1850, Howland/Anstice View, ca. 1850; 165966 (Box 246, Folder 13)
    - University Building, Exterior, ca. 1850; CB_UB_1_13_01; 165967; Howland, William; Engraving, 4.5 x. 2 inches. Image is from publication: The Old University Building and the Societys' Years on Washington Square in New-York Historical Society Quarterly, July 1948. (Box 246, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - Univeristy Building - Exterior, c. 1850, Richardson and Cox Engraving, 165964; Illustration, 7.5 x 8.25 inches. (Box 246, Folder 14)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1853; CB_UB_1_14_01; 165965; Black-and-white print, 7.5 x 8.5 inches of engraving (print). (Box 246, Folder 14, Item 1)
      Do Not Reproduce - Copyright for image is unclear.
      Washington Square (New York, N.Y.); Richardson & Cox.; New York University -- Buildings.
  - University Building - Exterior, 1851, Boetticher View/ Parade Grounds, 165962 (Box 246, Folder 15)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1851; CB_UB_1_15_01; 165963; Illustration, 9.5 x 6.38 inches. (Box 246, Folder 15, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1852, Wade View (Printed in Gleason's Pictorial, September 4, 1852), 165960 (Box 246, Folder 16)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1852; CB_UB_1_16_01; 165961; Engraving, 10 x 7.75 inches. Image in publication: Gleason's Pictorial, September 4, 1852. (Box 246, Folder 16, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1867, View from Manual of the Corporation/ New York Public Library, 165958 (Box 247, Folder 1)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1867; CB_UB_2_1_01; 165959; Engraving, 3.25 x 4 inches. Image is from page in Manual of the Corporation/New York Public Library (Box 247, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, c. 1867, Photograph (Front Elevation), ca. 1867; 165956 (Box 247, Folder 2)
    - University Building, Exterior, ca.1867; CB_UB_2_2_01; 165957; black-and-white print (photograph), 4.75 x 6 inches. (Box 247, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1870?, Milgram Donation, 165954 (Box 247, Folder 3)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1870?; CB_UB_2_3_01; 165955; black-and-white (photograph), 4.5 x 6 inches. (Box 247, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1878, Hunter Rendering, 165952 (Box 247, Folder 4)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1878; CB_UB_2_4_01; 165953; Hunter, Frederick Leo, 1858-1943; Engraving, 8 x 12 inches. (Box 247, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, c. 1880, Snow Scene, ca. 1880; 165949 (Box 247, Folder 5)
    - University Building, Exterior, ca. 1880; CB_UB_2_5_01; 165951; black-and-white print (photograph), 7.5 x 10.5 inches. (Box 247, Folder 5, Item 1)
    - University Building, Partial Exterior, ca. 1880; CB_UB_2_5_02; 165950; black-and-white print (photograph), 7.5 x 9.5 inches. (Box 247, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - University Building - Exterior, c. 1890, Photograph (Museum of the City of New York), ca. 1890; 165947 (Box 247, Folder 6)
    - University Building, Exterior, ca. 1890; CB_UB_2_6_01; 165948; Black-and-white print (photograph), 6.875 x 9.375 inches. (Box 247, Folder 6, Item 1)
      Do Not Reproduce - Property of Museum of the City of New York (MCNY)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1890, McKim, Mead, White, University Building renovation plans - transparencies, negatives, and prints, 165942 (Box 247, Folder 7)
    - University Building, Exterior Elevation and Building Plan (negatives), 1890; CB_UB_2_7_01; 165946; Color negative print, 8.5 x 10 inches. Image is of basement building plan. (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 1)
    - University Building, Building Renovation Plan, 1890; CB_UB_2_7_02; 165945; Color illustration, 7.5 x 10.5 inches. Image is of second floor plan. (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 2)
      Negatives.; New York University -- Buildings.
    - University Building, Building Renovation Plan, 1890; CB_UB_2_7_03; 165944; Color illustration, 7.375 x 10.375 inches. Image is of second floor building renovation plan. (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 3)
    - University Building, Building Renovation Plan, 1890; CB_UB_2_7_04; 165943; Color Negative print 8.5 x 10 inches. Image is of third floor renovation plans. (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 4)
    - University Building, Building Renovation Plan, 1890; CB_UB_2_7_05; 176986 (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 5)
    - University Building, Building Renovation Plan, 1890; CB_UB_2_7_06; 176987 (Box 247, Folder 7, Item 6)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1890, Photograph (Front Elevation with Park Benches), 165939 (Box 248, Folder 1)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1893?-1894; CB_UB_3_1_01; 165941; black-and-white print (photograph), 5 x 7 inches. (Box 248, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - University Building, Exterior view looking east, undated; CB_UB_3_1_02; 165940; black-and-white print (photograph), 7 x 8.75 inches. (Box 248, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1891, "Number Five", 165937 (Box 248, Folder 2)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1891; CB_UB_3_2_01; 165938; black-and-white print (photograph), 4.575 x 7.575 inches. From back "Number 5 is a front view of the University Building taken in 1891. It is the finest photograph ever taken of the old structure." (Box 248, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1891, View with Asbury Methodist Church, 165935 (Box 248, Folder 3)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1891; CB_UB_3_3_01; 165936; black-and-white print (photograph), 4.25 x 6.75 inches. Image is from Asbury Methodist Church across Washington Square Park. (Box 248, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1892, "421" (in lower left corner of image), 165933 (Box 248, Folder 4)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1892; CB_UB_3_4_01; 165934; black-and-white print (photograph), 7.5 x 9.5 inches. (Box 248, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1892 Negative 4/1142 (Partial View), 165931 (Box 248, Folder 5)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1892; CB_UB_3_5_01; 165932; black-and-white print (photograph), 7.5 x 9.5 inches. Image is partial view of the west wing of the building. (Box 248, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1892 or 1893 Roof of South Wing - Photo taken by Dr. D.W. Hering, 1892? 1893?; 165929 (Box 248, Folder 6)
    - University Building, Exterior Roof of South Wing, 1892-1893?; CB_UB_3_6_01; 165930; D.W. (Daniel Webster) Hering, 1850-1938; black-and-white print (photograph), 5.875 x 8.575 inches. View of South Wing Roof. (Box 248, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1893 Snow Scene, 165927 (Box 248, Folder 7)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1893; CB_UB_3_7_01; 165928; black-and-white print (photograph), 7.25 x 9.5 inches. (Box 248, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1893?, 165925 (Box 248, Folder 8)
    - University Building, Exterior, 1893?; CB_UB_3_8_01; 165926; Negative print, 4 x 4.75 inches. Image is a view looking east with a horse and carriage. (Box 248, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - University Building - Exterior, 1893? "Richard Original", 165923 (Box 248, Folder 9)